Finding aid to the Elizabeth Stephens papers CA.MS.00019
Smith College Archives
Elizabeth Stephens papers
1921-1926
Smith College Archives
Stephens, Elizabeth, 1902-
CA.MS.00019
1.875 linear feet (5 containers)
Smith graduate. Contains correspondence, class notes, photgraphs, and academic work.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ann B. Hamilton donated the letters of Elizabeth Stephens to the College Archives in April 1999. Other papers were donated to the College Archives over a period of years.
Biographical / Historical
Elizabeth Stephens was born on March 10, 1902 in Montclair, New Jersey to Thomas Wilcox Stephens, a manufacturer, and Elizabeth (Henderson) Stephens. Prior to her enrollment at Smith College in 1920, Stephens attended The Shipley School (Bryn Mawr, PA), Miss Walker's School (Simsbury, Connecticut), and Milton Academy (Milton, Massachusetts). Stephens graduated from Smith College on June 19, 1924 with an AB and married Ogden Bigelow in 1926. Ogden Junior was born in 1928 and their daughter, Ann (AB '51), in 1929.
Related Material
80. Class of 1924 Records
Scope and Contents
The Elizabeth Stephens Papers are primarily related to her years spent at Smith College, dating from 1921 to 1926. Types of material include correspondence; class notes; photographs; and academic work.
The majority of this collection is comprised of correspondence. Included are exchanges with Stephens' future husband, Ogden Bigelow and letters from both the Stephens and the Bigelow families pertaining to the wedding.
Stephens, Elizabeth, 1902-; Smith College--Students.
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1921 (Box 1971.1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 1971.1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1923-01-1923-02 (Box 1971.1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1923-03-1923-04 (Box 1971.1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1923-05 (Box 1971.1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1923-06-1923-07 (Box 1971.1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1923-08 (Box 1971.1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1923-09 (Box 1971.1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1923-10 (Box 1971.1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1923-11 (Box 1971.1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1923-12 (Box 1971.1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1924-01 (Box 1971.2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1924-02 (Box 1971.2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1924-03 (Box 1971.2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1924-04 (Box 1971.2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1924-05 (Box 1971.2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1924-06 (Box 1971.2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1924-07 (Box 1971.2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1924-08-01-1924-08-17 (Box 1971.3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1924-08-18-1924-08-29 (Box 1971.3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1924-09-1924-12 (Box 1971.3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1925-01-1925-06 (Box 1971.3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1925-07-01-1925-07-23 (Box 1971.3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1925-08-01-1925-08-07 (Box 1971.3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1925-08-08-1925-08-14 (Box 1971.4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1925-08-15-1925-08-22 (Box 1971.4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1925-08-24-1925-08-31 (Box 1971.4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1925-09-1925-12 (Box 1971.4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1926-01-30-1926-08-30 (Box 1971.4, Folder 5)
- Class Notes Art 22: Introduction to the History of Art, 1922-23 (Box 1971.5, Folder 1)
- Class Notes Art 22: General History of Art, 1922-23 (Box 1971.5, Folder 2)
- Class Notes Art 310: The Development of House Furniture, 1923-24 (Box 1971.5, Folder 3)
- Class Notes Geology II: General Geology, 1922-23 (Box 1971.5, Folder 4)
- Class Notes Sociology 37a: Population and Vital Statistics, 1923-24 (Box 1971.5, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1922-1923 (Box 1971.5, Folder 6)
- Paper "The Essence of Confucianism as Taught by its Founder", undated (Box 1971.5, Folder 7)
- Paper "The Place of Italy in the Development of Painting", undated (Box 1971.5, Folder 8)
- Line-A-Day Diary, 1921-1924 (Box 1971.5, Folder 9)
- Photographs, undated (Box 1971.5, Folder 10)